Speaking of robotics, let's talk about what we can do in robotics. We cannot yet
send them through time.
But we can maybe do more than you
may think. So what is robotics? Well to
actually build robotics there's a lot of
say mechanical engineering,
the mechatronics, building the gears and and
sorting out the forces and soldering things.
That's all very important,
but it's not really what we do in this class. In this class, we look at
the part of robotics which is AI.
And that's the control of the robots, figuring out,
once you've got this robotic platform,
what control signals do you send down the wire
to do whatever you're trying to do--
pick up the cup, or sweep the floor, or whatever it is.
It turns out that simulating robots is
much easier than actually
deploying robots. We alluded to this
earlier were once you're in the real world,
suddenly it's not just planning
for how you move that arm, but it's acknowledging that
maybe your sensors are a little bit
wrong or maybe the arm will slip during
motion, and everything is much, much
harder in reality than in simulation.
Also when you mess up it's more expensive in
reality than in simulations. These robots
do not come cheap.
What kind of things we build? We can build
autonomous vehicles. We'll talk about a couple kinds in this course.
We can build rescue technologies, we can
build soccer-playing robots which is
of course a critical goal of AI, and we can automate
a bunch of stuff. I mean in some sense there's
robots all over. Your dishwasher is a
robot for cleaning dishes. It's just,
to a first approximation you blast
water at them and now they're clean, so we
often don't think of that as much of an AI task,
though there are control problems even in a
dishwasher.
In this class we're going to ignore the
mechanical and mechatronic aspect of robotics
and we're only gonna think about the planning
and control aspects.
Let me show you for today, a kind of
sense of what kinds of things you can do.
I love this. Does anyone know what this is?
This is RoboCup, this is the Aibo league. They're so cute.
I'm going to play a little bit of an Aibo
soccer match.
The first thing to notice is that
they're in formation,
they're going to play soccer. It's a team thing; they have to coordinate.
It's kind of like watching
five-year olds play soccer right.
Like the white goalie, what are you doing,
what are you doing.
Fortunately you don't actually need a goalie when you're playing against these guys.
Goal!
So, what to learn from here. First of all,
multiple agents are harder to control than one--
it's actually hard to do much with an Aibo--but, multiple agents are harder to control.
You've got to coordinate.
This this level of multi-agent control.
You also have to get the individual robot to simply walk along, and like find where the ball is,
do the vision and the calibration.
All of that stuff is hard.
Even when you're not thinking about
soccer strategy.
And so this is an example of that.
Something else I'd like to use these
Aibos to show is that remember we talked
about the difference between
an AI acting in an optimal way
vervus like a biomimetic kind of human-like--or in this case I guess dog-like--way?
It turns out, when you're playing soccer,
you know, a dog might move a ball a
certain way. But if you've got an Aibo,
you don't want to move the ball
like a dog.
You want to move the ball in the best way possible. And you'll never guess what it is.
And then you've got to turn around and see what
the heck happened. So they're all going to
go over to the ball now.
So, again, the point here is,
optimal,
sometimes you kick it the other way.
Not biomimetic.
We talked about autonomous cars. So here's
some footage from a Google autonomous car,
and you'll notice,
it may not be Telegraph Avenue, but
these things are kind of around you driving and
the cool thing is
you probably don't even know it. Sometimes you
look over into the next car and the robot waves back,
but you know barring that you may
just not even know.
Fully autonomous driving.
This is showing some of the sensors that are available.
I don't know, like my palms sweat while watching this driving even
with a driver there right.
So, autonomous driving,
better than you might think.
We talked about towel folding, so
let me show you
a bit of towel folding from Pieter Abbeel's lab.
This is the PR2,
folding towels.
it turns out when you're a robot,
the hard part about folding is not the
folding part, but in the figuring out
where the corners are in the first place.
So you'll see the robot kinda like
twirls the towel until it finds a corner, and then once it finds a corner, boom boom boom.
well, you know, it's sped up 200x so it's not boom boom boom, but
booom, booom, booom.
So it folds them, stacks them,
beautiful.
It is currently not the most
cost-efficient way to fold towels.
Okay now let me show you the bad boy
here. So this is a
Boston Dynamics robot.
Basically if Terminators had really
really tiny heads,
they'd look something like this.
So let's see what this thing can do.
It can pose.
This robot, it has kind of a big range of
motion.
It can be stable doing these rotations
which is amazingly hard--people do it.
It can walk.
If I saw that walking towards me I might
be a little worried.
it can strike its pose and kneel down and do
things. It does push ups in its spare time!
Okay you know when your robot does pushups for fun,
you've got a certain kind of robot.
So, really amazing stuff. It may not be obvious from watching this but it is amazingly
hard just to get a robot to walk. That why many robots have wheels,
an easier platform of some kind. To be able to walk, like this, this is amazing stuff they have.